<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.1//EN" "document-v11.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Barcode4J Documentation Overview</title>
    <authors>
      <person id="cleeds" name="Web Maestro Clay" email="the_webmaestro@users.sourceforge.net"/>
    </authors>
  </header>
  <body>
    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <p>This page describes the documentation structure for <strong>Barcode4J</strong>.</p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Barcode4J Documentation Links</title>
      <dl>
        <dt><link href="site:general">The Barcode XML Format</link></dt>
        <dd>describes the XML format used by <strong>Barcode4J</strong> to define barcodes. It also contains notes about the message format supported by each symbology.</dd>
        <dt><link href="site:output-formats">Output Formats</link></dt>
        <dd>gives information about the various output formats supported by <strong>Barcode4J</strong> and tells you how to implement additional output formats.</dd>
        <dt><link href="site:design">Design</link></dt>
        <dd>describes how <strong>Barcode4J</strong> was designed to implement and configure barcodes using XML, in a way that the whole package can easily be integrated into a bigger work.</dd>
      </dl>
      <section>
        <title>Scenarios</title>
        <p>These pages show Use Cases for generating barcodes using <strong>Barcode4J</strong>:</p>
        <dl>
          <dt><link href="site:xsl-fo">XSL-FO</link></dt>
          <dd>shows a use case for generating barcodes in <jump href="ext:svg">SVG format</jump> format for <jump href="ext:xsl-fo">XSL-FO</jump> documents.</dd>
          <dt><link href="site:svg-dom">SVG DOM</link></dt>
          <dd>describes the generation of an <jump href="ext:svg">SVG format</jump> barcode in Java.</dd>
        </dl>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Creating Barcodes</title>
        <p>These pages describe the differing dependencies and options for using <strong>Barcode4J</strong>:</p>
        <dl>
          <dt><link href="site:fop-ext">...with FOP</link></dt>
          <dd>describes how to generate barcodes within an <jump href="ext:xsl-fo">XSL-FO</jump> document with that is processed with <fork href="ext:fop">Apache FOP</fork>.</dd>
          <dt><link href="site:xalan-ext">...with Xalan-J</link></dt>
          <dd>describes how to generate barcodes in <jump href="ext:svg">SVG format</jump> within an XSLT stylesheet that is processed with <fork href="ext:xalan">Apache Xalan-J</fork></dd>
          <dt><link href="site:saxon-ext">...with SAXON</link></dt>
          <dd>describes how to generate barcodes in <jump href="ext:svg">SVG format</jump> within an XSLT stylesheet that is processed with the <fork href="ext:saxon">SAXON XSLT Processor from Michael Kay</fork>.</dd>
          <dt><link href="site:servlet">...with a Servlet</link></dt>
          <dd>describes a simple Servlet that can be used to generate barcodes in <jump href="ext:svg">SVG</jump>, EPS or any supported bitmap format with a URL.</dd>
          <dt><link href="site:cli">...from the Command Line</link></dt>
          <dd>describes how to use the command line interface that comes with <strong>Barcode4J</strong>.</dd>
          <dt><link href="site:embedding">...embedding in Java (XML API)</link></dt>
          <dd>describes how to integrate <strong>Barcode4J</strong> in a Java application using the XML API.</dd>
          <dt><link href="site:embedding-bean">...embedding in Java (Bean API)</link></dt>
          <dd>describes how to integrate <strong>Barcode4J</strong> in a Java application using the JavaBeans API.</dd>
          <dt><link href="site:ant">...with Apache Ant</link></dt>
          <dd>describes how to generate barcodes within an <jump href="http://ant.apache.org">Ant</jump> script.</dd>
        </dl>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
